Hello everyone, welcome to another great lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎来到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be talking about an ER, an emergency room.
今天我们要聊聊急诊室。
Exactly, we're bringing you our very own ER drama here at EnglishPod.
没错，我们将在EnglishPod上演我们自己的急诊室剧情。
Yeah, doctor shows are very popular with people, medical terms and all that stuff.
是啊，医疗剧很受欢迎，医学词汇什么的。
Yeah, so we're going to teach you some words that you might hear commonly in medical shows
是的，所以我们会教大家一些在医疗剧里常听到的词。
on TV or in movies.
在电视或电影里。
This is really common language in television.
这在电视里是很常见的语言。
Or even at a hospital, right?
甚至在医院里也是，对吧？
Well yeah, but let's hope our listeners don't have to face this.
嗯，但希望我们的听众不用面对这些。
Okay, so let's preview some words in Vocabulary Preview.
好的，那我们先在词汇预览里看几个词。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Alright, so what's our first word?
好，第一个词是什么？
Okay, the first word is CPR.
第一个词是CPR。
CPR.
CPR。
So, that's pretty easy, what does that mean?
这个很简单，它是什么意思？
Well, it's short for cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
它是心肺复苏术的缩写。
Okay.
好的。
If that means anything to you.
如果你知道这个词的话。
Well cardio is related to the heart.
Cardio和心脏有关。
Cardio refers to the lungs.
Pulmonary指的是肺。
Yep.
对。
Resuscitation means to come back to life.
Resuscitation意思是复苏。
Yes, so basically CPR is, you know when someone stops breathing, you put your mouth on their
是的，所以CPR基本上就是，当有人停止呼吸时，你把嘴对嘴
mouth and you breathe inside their lungs.
往他们肺里吹气。
Okay, to give them air.
给他们供气。
Yeah.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So, CPR.
所以，CPR。
That's CPR.
就是CPR。
Okay, so let's take a look at our next word, BP.
好，我们来看下一个词，BP。
BP.
BP。
So, BP is short for?
BP是……的缩写？
Blood pressure.
血压。
That's just the way that doctors use it in the emergency room.
这是医生在急诊室里的用法。
Exactly, pretty simple.
没错，很简单。
Okay, so blood pressure.
好的，血压。
And our last word, acute respiratory failure.
最后一个词，急性呼吸衰竭。
Acute respiratory failure.
急性呼吸衰竭。
So, what is that exactly?
那到底是什么？
That sounds complicated.
听起来很复杂。
Basically it's really serious, they stop breathing.
基本上就是非常严重，他们停止呼吸。
You stop breathing.
你停止呼吸。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So, if you go into acute respiratory failure, then the doctor or somebody has to perform
所以，如果你出现急性呼吸衰竭，医生或其他人必须进行
CPR.
心肺复苏。
Right.
好的。
All right, cool.
好的，酷。
Okay, so we've previewed these three great words, now let's listen to our dialogue for
好的，我们已经预览了这三个很棒的词，现在让我们来听一下对话。
the first time.
第一次。
It's going to be really fast and you're going to have a lot of drama in it, so don't worry
它会非常快，而且里面会有很多戏剧性情节，所以别担心。
if you don't understand everything.
如果你不是什么都懂。
Yeah, we're going to come back and teach you some of the important language.
是的，我们会回来教你们一些重要的语言点。
Help!
救命！
Are you a doctor?
你是医生吗？
My poor little Frankie, he's just stopped breathing.
我可怜的小弗兰基，他刚刚停止呼吸了。
Oh my gosh, help me.
哦天哪，救救我。
I tried to perform CPR, but I just, I don't know if I could get any air into his lungs.
我试着做心肺复苏，但就是，我不知道有没有把空气送进他的肺里。
Oh, Frankie.
哦，弗兰基。
Ellen, get him hooked up to a monitor.
艾伦，把他连上监护仪。
Somebody page Dr. Hauser.
谁呼叫一下豪泽医生。
Get the patient to hold still.
让病人别动。
I can't get a pulse.
我摸不到脉搏。
Okay, he's on the monitor.
好了，他上监护仪了。
His BP is falling.
他的血压在下降。
He's flatlining.
他心跳停止了。
No, Frankie!
不，弗兰基！
Doctor, do something!
医生，快想想办法！
Someone get her out of here.
快把她带出去。
Get me the defibrillator.
把除颤器给我。
Okay, clear.
好了，离开。
Again, clear.
再来，离开。
Come on, dammit, I'm not letting go of you.
加油，该死的，我不会放弃你的。
Clear.
离开。
I got a pulse.
有脉搏了。
Okay, what's happening?
好了，发生什么事了？
The patient is in acute respiratory failure.
病人处于急性呼吸衰竭状态。
I think we're going to have to intubate.
我想我们得给他插管了。
All right, we're going to have to intubate.
好吧，我们得插管了。
I'm going to have to intubate.
我得给他插管。
Okay, we're going to have to intubate.
好的，我们得插管了。
I'm going to have to intubate.
我得给他插管。
I'm going to have to intubiate.
Don't worry, he's not dying.
别担心，他还没死。
All right, tube's in.
好了，管子插进去了。
Bag him.
给他捏气囊。
Somebody give him 10 cc's shot of adrenaline.
谁给他注射10毫升肾上腺素。
Let's go!
快！
People, move!
大家，动起来！
Move!
快！
Doctor, oh thank God!
医生，哦，谢天谢地！
How is he?
他怎么样了？
We've managed to stabilize Frankie, but he's not out of the woods yet.
我们设法稳定了弗兰基的情况，但他还没有脱离危险。
He's still in critical condition.
他仍然处于危急状态。
We're moving him to intensive care, but-
我们要把他转到重症监护室，但是——
Doctor, just do whatever it takes.
医生，请不惜一切代价。
I just want my little Frankie to be okay.
我只想让我的小弗兰基好起来。
I couldn't imagine life without my little hamster.
我无法想象没有我的小仓鼠的生活。
Wow, so much drama over a little hamster.
哇，为了一只小仓鼠这么大惊小怪。
Yeah, a little pet, hey?
是啊，一只小宠物，嗯？
A little pet, a little hamster.
一只小宠物，一只小仓鼠。
Well, you know what?
嗯，你知道吗？
I can relate to this owner
我能理解这位主人
and I'm gonna tell you a little bit more about that later.
我待会儿再跟你们详细说说。
Yeah, I know you have a really good story about this.
是啊，我知道你有个关于这个的好故事。
Yeah, but in the meantime,
是啊，不过与此同时，
let's look at some great language in Language Takeaway.
让我们看看《语言小贴士》里的一些精彩语言。
All right, so let's take a look at our first word,
好的，我们来看看第一个词，
intubate.
插管。
Intubate.
So this is a medical procedure.
所以这是一个医疗程序。
Exactly.
没错。
When a patient can't breathe properly,
当病人无法正常呼吸时，
sometimes the doctor takes a long tube
有时医生会拿一根长管
and puts it into their mouth and down their pipes,
放进他们的嘴里，顺着呼吸道往下，
I guess, down their breathing tube.
我想，是放进他们的呼吸管里。
Right.
对。
So that they can breathe better.
这样他们就能更好地呼吸。
Okay, so that's to intubate.
好的，这就是插管。
Yes.
是的。
Okay, so once they've intubated the patient,
好的，一旦他们给病人插管后，
they start to bag him.
他们就开始给他捏皮球。
Yeah, bag him.
对，捏皮球。
Bag him.
捏皮球。
Does that mean they like put a bag
这是不是意味着他们把一个袋子
over the person's head or something?
套在病人头上之类的？
No, no, no, no, no.
不不不不不。
So there's a bag attached to this intubation tube
这个插管上连着一个皮球，
and you squeeze it to put air into the lungs.
你挤压它就能把空气送进肺部。
Okay, so you squeeze this bag
好的，所以你挤压这个皮球，
and it puts air through the tube.
空气就通过管子进去。
I think this is just medical slang.
我想这只是医学术语。
Yeah, I guess bag him.
对，我猜就是捏皮球。
Yeah, but you hear it all the time on TV,
对，但你在电视上经常听到，
so it's important our listeners know it.
所以让我们的听众知道很重要。
Okay, let's look at our next word, critical condition.
好的，我们来看下一个词，病危。
Critical condition.
病危。
The patient's in critical condition.
病人情况危急。
This condition means it's serious.
这种情况意味着很严重。
Right, if a patient is in critical condition,
对，如果病人情况危急，
they're either really, really hurt or really, really sick
他们要么伤得很重，要么病得很重，
and they could die pretty soon.
而且可能很快就会死。
Okay, so you don't want to be in critical condition.
好的，所以你不想处于病危状态。
No.
不想。
Let's take a look at our next word, stabilize.
我们来看下一个词，稳定。
Stabilize.
稳定。
稳定病情。
Stabilize.
So when the doctors stabilize a patient,
所以当医生稳定病人的病情时，
they take that patient out of danger.
他们让病人脱离危险。
Exactly, when a patient is stabilized,
没错，当病人病情稳定后，
they probably won't die in five minutes.
他们大概不会在五分钟内死掉。
Okay.
好的。
But they could still be really sick.
但他们可能仍然病得很重。
They could be in critical condition, right?
他们可能处于危急状态，对吧？
But it's under control.
但情况已经得到控制。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
嗯。
Stabilize.
稳定病情。
Let's look at our last word, ICU.
我们来看最后一个词，ICU。
ICU.
ICU。
Intensive care unit.
重症监护室。
Okay, that's what it means, intensive care unit.
好的，就是这个意思，重症监护室。
Yep.
是的。
So this is a place where patients
所以这里是接收
who are in critical condition are taken.
处于危急状态的病人的地方。
Right.
对。
So what's the difference between an ICU and a regular room?
那么ICU和普通病房有什么区别？
Well, I don't know, I've never been in one.
嗯，我不知道，我没住过。
But I think like patients are monitored regularly
但我觉得病人会被定期监测，
and I think there's, you know, maybe more,
而且我想，你知道，可能更多，
maybe there are more nurses and fewer patients.
可能护士更多，病人更少。
There's just a higher level of care.
只是护理水平更高。
A higher level of care.
护理水平更高。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, so it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again.
好了，现在该再听一遍我们的对话了。
Now, try to catch all of these medical terms
现在，试着找出所有这些医学术语，
that we've just talked about,
就是我们刚刚讨论过的，
and then we'll come back and explain a few phrases.
然后我们会回来解释一些短语。
♪♪
Help!
救命！
Are you a doctor?
你是医生吗？
My poor little Frankie has just stopped breathing.
我可怜的小弗兰基刚刚停止呼吸了。
Oh my gosh, help me.
哦天哪，救救我。
I tried to perform CPR, but I just,
我试着做心肺复苏，但我就是，
I don't know if I could get any air into his lungs.
我不知道我能不能把空气送进他的肺里。
Oh, Frankie.
哦，弗兰基。
Ellen, get him hooked up to a monitor.
艾伦，把他连上监护仪。
Somebody page Dr. Hauser.
有人呼叫豪瑟医生。
Get the patient to hold still.
让病人别动。
I can't get a pulse.
我摸不到脉搏。
Okay, he's on the monitor.
好了，他上监护仪了。
His BP's falling.
他的血压在下降。
He's flatlining.
他的心跳成直线了。
No, Frankie!
不，弗兰基！
Doctor, do something!
医生，快想想办法！
Someone get her out of here.
谁把她带出去。
Get me the defibrillator.
把除颤器给我。
Okay, clear.
好的，离开。
Again, clear.
再来，离开。
Come on, dammit, I'm not letting go of you.
加油，该死的，我不会放弃你的。
Clear!
离开！
I've got a pulse.
有脉搏了。
Okay, what's happening?
好了，发生什么事了？
The patient is in acute respiratory failure.
病人出现急性呼吸衰竭。
I think we're going to have to intubate.
我想我们得给他插管。
All right, tube's in.
好了，插管进去了。
Bag him.
给他捏气囊。
Somebody give him 10 cc's shot of adrenaline.
谁给他注射10毫升肾上腺素。
Let's go, people, move, move!
大家动起来，快，快！
Doctor, oh, thank God.
医生，哦，谢天谢地。
How is he?
他怎么样了？
We've managed to stabilize Frankie,
我们设法稳定了弗兰基的情况。
but he's not out of the woods yet.
但他还没有脱离危险。
He's still in critical condition.
他仍然处于危急状态。
We're moving him to intensive care, but-
我们要把他转到重症监护室，但是——
Doctor, just do whatever it takes.
医生，请不惜一切代价。
I just want my little Frankie to be okay.
我只想让我的小弗兰基没事。
I couldn't imagine life without my little hamster.
我无法想象没有我的小仓鼠的生活。
Okay, so there are some really good phrasal verbs
好的，这段对话中有一些非常好的短语动词。
in this dialogue.
是的，几个不错的短语动词。
Yeah, a couple of good phrasal verbs.
好的，那我们来看看这些短语动词。
Okay, so let's take a look at these phrasal verbs
in putting it together.
在把它组装起来。
Putting it together.
把它组装起来。
All right, so what's our first phrasal verb today?
好的，那我们今天的第一个动词短语是什么？
Hook up.
So to hook up.
所以是 hook up。
So when we talk about hooking something up,
当我们说 hook something up 时，
we are usually talking about something that's
通常指的是某种
we are usually talking about electronics, right Marco?
通常指的是电子产品，对吧 Marco？
Yeah, you usually hook up your TV or your computer.
是的，通常你会 hook up 你的电视或电脑。
So why don't we listen to some examples
那我们听一些例子
of how we would use hook up.
看看怎么使用 hook up。
Example one.
例子一。
I finally got a Nintendo Wii.
我终于买到了任天堂 Wii。
Come on, help me hook it up to the TV.
快来，帮我把它连接到电视上。
Example two.
例子二。
I don't know how to hook up this new DVD player.
我不知道怎么连接这个新 DVD 播放器。
Can you help me?
你能帮我吗？
Example three.
例子三。
I just hooked up my new HDTV.
我刚连接好了我的新高清电视。
Wanna come over and watch a movie?
想过来看电影吗？
Great, so you can see that there are a few different
很好，所以你可以看到有几种不同的
variations of this pattern here with the word hook up
这个模式的变体，关于 hook up 这个词
because it's a phrasal verb.
因为它是一个动词短语。
Exactly.
没错。
And I think the same patterns can apply
而且我认为同样的模式也适用于
to our next phrasal verb.
我们的下一个动词短语。
Hold still.
So the doctor needed the patient to hold still.
所以医生需要病人 hold still。
Right, to stop moving.
对，就是不要动。
Stop moving, exactly.
不要动，没错。
Okay, let's listen to some more examples of hold still
好的，我们来听更多关于 hold still 的例子
because again, it's a really great phrasal verb
因为同样，这是一个非常好的动词短语
that you can change up a little bit.
你可以稍微变化一下。
Example one.
例子一。
If you don't hold still,
如果你不动的话，
I can't see if you have something in your eye.
我看不到你眼睛里有没有东西。
Example two.
例子二。
Hold still while she cuts your hair
她给你剪头发时别动
or else she might make a mistake.
否则她可能会剪错。
Example three.
例子三。
Hold still, you have a bee on your back.
别动，你背上有一只蜜蜂。
Okay, hold still, great word.
好的，别动，好词。
Yep.
嗯。
All right, one final phrase for you.
好了，最后一个短语给你。
Out of the woods.
脱离危险。
So when someone's out of the woods, they're...
所以当某人脱离危险时，他们就是……
Free from danger.
脱离了危险。
Uh-huh, safe.
嗯哼，安全了。
Okay, safe.
好的，安全了。
I guess it's kind of a saying.
我想这算是一种说法。
Yeah.
是的。
Like I'm out of the woods, I'm free, I'm safe.
就像我脱离危险了，我自由了，我安全了。
I guess there are two variants of this phrase.
我想这个短语有两种变体。
We can say, I'm out of the woods or we're out of the woods
我们可以说，我脱离危险了或者我们脱离危险了
or I guess we're not out of the woods yet.
或者我想我们还没脱离危险。
Uh-huh, so, okay.
嗯哼，所以，好的。
Out of the woods.
脱离危险。
Okay, so now it's time for us to listen to our dialogue
好的，现在让我们再听一遍对话
again and when we come back,
等我们回来的时候，
Erica's gonna tell us about her ER story.
Erica会告诉我们她在急诊室的故事。
Help, are you a doctor?
救命，你是医生吗？
My poor little Frankie, he's just stopped breathing.
我可怜的小Frankie，他刚刚停止呼吸了。
Oh my gosh, help me.
哦天哪，救救我。
I tried to perform CPR, but I just,
我试着做心肺复苏，但我就是，
I don't know if I could get any air into his lungs.
我不知道我能不能把空气送进他的肺里。
Oh, Frankie.
哦，Frankie。
Ellen, get him hooked up to a monitor.
Ellen，把他连接到监护仪上。
Somebody page Dr. Hauser.
谁呼叫一下Hauser医生。
Get the patient to hold still.
让病人别动。
I can't get a pulse.
我摸不到脉搏。
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
对不起，对不起。
I can't get a pulse.
我摸不到脉搏。
Okay, he's on the monitor.
好了，他在监护仪上。
His BP's falling.
他的血压在下降。
He's flatlining.
他心跳停止了。
No, Frankie!
不，弗兰基！
Doctor, do something!
医生，快想想办法！
Someone get her out of here.
谁把她带出去。
Get me the defibrillator.
把除颤器给我。
Okay, clear.
好，闪开。
Again, clear.
再来，闪开。
Come on, dammit, I'm not letting go of you.
加油，该死的，我不会放弃你的。
Clear.
闪开。
I got a pulse.
有脉搏了。
Okay, what's happening?
好，现在什么情况？
Patient is in acute respiratory failure.
病人出现急性呼吸衰竭。
I think we're going to have to intubate.
我想我们得插管了。
Alright, tube's in.
好了，插管进去了。
Bag him.
给他捏气囊。
Somebody give him 10 cc's shot of adrenaline.
谁给他注射10毫升肾上腺素。
Let's go, people, move, move!
快，大家动起来，快，快！
Doctor, oh thank God!
医生，哦，谢天谢地！
How is he?
他怎么样了？
We've managed to stabilize Frankie,
我们设法稳定了弗兰基的情况，
but he's not out of the woods yet.
但他还没有脱离危险。
He's still in critical condition.
他仍然处于危急状态。
We're moving him to intensive care, but...
我们正要把他转到重症监护室，但是……
Doctor, just do whatever it takes.
医生，请不惜一切代价。
I just want my little Frankie to be okay.
我只想让我的小弗兰基没事。
I couldn't imagine life without my little hamster.
我无法想象没有我的小仓鼠的生活。
Okay, Erica, so what happened?
好了，埃里卡，发生什么事了？
What emergency did you have?
你遇到了什么紧急情况？
Well, it was with my cat.
嗯，是关于我的猫。
Your cat.
你的猫。
Yes, I had some people over for dinner,
是的，我请了一些人来家里吃饭，
and it was maybe 1.30 in the morning,
当时大概是凌晨一点半，
and I went downstairs to let them out
我下楼去放它们出去
and show them where the taxis were,
并告诉它们出租车在哪里，
and then I came up and I saw that the cat was gone,
然后我上楼发现猫不见了，
and it turned out that the cat fell out of the window.
结果发现猫从窗户掉下去了。
Fell out of the window.
从窗户掉下去了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Alright, but our listeners have to know,
好吧，但我们的听众必须知道，
what story or what floor do you live on?
你住在几楼？
The 20th floor.
20楼。
The 20th.
Yeah, so this is really dangerous, right?
是啊，这真的很危险，对吧？
That's really high up.
那太高了。
So I went outside and I was calling for my cat,
所以我跑出去喊我的猫，
and I was like, Mr. Finn, where are you?
我说，芬恩先生，你在哪里？
How did you know he fell out?
你怎么知道它掉下去了？
I just knew.
我就是知道。
Yeah?
是吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
Mother's instinct.
母亲的直觉。
I guess so.
我想是吧。
So he was calling back to me, and so I picked him up
它回应了我，所以我把它抱起来
and brought him to the house,
带回了家，
and we had to bring him to the vet,
我们不得不带它去看兽医，
and it was 2.30, 3 in the morning at this time,
那时是凌晨两点半、三点，
and the vet was not very happy that we woke him up out of bed.
兽医被我们从床上叫起来很不高兴。
But that was a really good emergency, though.
但那确实是紧急情况。
Yeah.
是啊。
So anyway, we brought him to the vet.
总之，我们带它去了兽医那里。
He was in critical condition for a couple of days,
它情况危急了好几天，
and then we had to keep him in the vet's ICU for about a week.
然后我们不得不把它留在兽医的ICU大约一周。
He broke his back.
它摔断了背。
He broke two of his legs.
它摔断了两条腿。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah, and so he was in the hospital for three weeks
是啊，所以它在医院住了三周
and then at home on bed rest for another three weeks.
然后在家卧床休息又三周。
But now he's good as new.
但现在它完好如初了。
Good as new.
完好如初。
Yeah.
是啊。
He used up one of his seven lives.
它用掉了九条命中的一条。
Nine lives.
九条命。
Nine?
九条命？
Nine.
九条命。
Yeah.
是啊。
I think maybe eight of his nine lives.
我觉得他可能用掉了八条命。
He's only got one left.
他只剩一条命了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Wow, that's an interesting story.
哇，这故事真有意思。
I guess that's the inspiration under this dialogue.
我想这就是这段对话的灵感来源。
Exactly.
没错。
Sometimes we Anglos really treat our cats
有时候我们西方人真的把猫
and our hamsters and our dogs like they're our children.
还有仓鼠和狗当成自己的孩子。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
No, that's good.
不，这挺好的。
Well, I'm glad Mr. Finn is OK and he's
嗯，我很高兴芬恩先生没事了，他
walking and good as new.
又能走路了，跟新的一样。
Yep, good as new.
对，跟新的一样。
So maybe our users have some stories about their pets
所以也许我们的用户有一些关于宠物
being taken to the hospital.
被送进医院的故事。
I want to hear.
我想听听。
Yeah, that should be interesting.
是啊，那应该挺有意思的。
I've never had a pet actually break a leg or anything,
我从来没有宠物摔断腿之类的经历，
so don't have any pet stories this time.
所以这次没有宠物故事可讲。
But we want to hear what you think,
但我们想听听你们的想法，
so come to EnglishPod.com, leave all your questions
所以请访问EnglishPod.com，留下你们的所有问题
and comments and your stories.
和评论以及你们的故事。
Yes.
是的。
And we'll be there to answer them.
我们会在那里回答。
So guys, thanks for listening.
好了，朋友们，感谢收听。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
拜。